Guide to the American Civil Liberties Union of North Carolina Records, 1960-2020; 1960-ongoing and undated RL.00012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Material Series, 1978-2004, 2 boxes
  - Microcassette from box 273, New Bern, Ten Commandments (Box 352)
  - Two audiocassettes from box 283, Ten Commandments (Box 353)
  - VHS from boxes 292-297, School uniforms and religious rights (Box 353)
  - Two VHS from box 337, Unlawful search and seizure (Box 353)
  - CD and calendar, State Bar Admissions (Box 353)
  - Audiocassette, interrogation #13, hearing, 1998, Aug. 18 (Box 353)
  - VHS, Baker Elin, interrogation #9 (Box 353)
  - VHS, school finance, 4/5 (Box 353)
- Print Material Series, 1968-2002, 9 boxes
  Various reports, statements, pamphlets, newsletters and periodicals from the inactive files of the ACLU of NC, chiefly assembled during the 1990s by the Executive Director's office. Arranged alphabetically by title, with a final section housing miscellaneous titles arranged by topic.
  - Print Material Alphabetically by Title
    - Artistic Freedom Under Attack, 1994-1995, 2 folders (Box 354)
    - Chowder, Ken, The ACLU Defends Everybody, Smithsonian (Box 354)
    - Church and State, 1996-2002 (Box 354)
    - Employment and Wages in NC, 1997 (Box 354)
    - First Principles, 1975-1989, folders 1-4 of 5 (Box 354)
    - First Principles, 1975-1989, folder 5 of 5 (Box 355)
    - Jail and Prisoner Law Bulletin, 1980-1987, 4 folders (Box 355)
    - Liberty (ACLU of NC newsletter), 1966-2002, 4 folders (Box 355)
    - Liberty (ACLU of NC newsletter) and contributing articles, 1995-2000, 5 folders (Box 356)
    - NCLU Executor of the Bill of Rights, 1969 (Box 356)
    - NC State Bar newsletter, 1989-1993, 2 folders (Box 356)
    - NC state capitol area telephone directory, 1991 (Box 356)
    - Politics or Christ (Box 356)
    - Prison Law Monitor, 1978-1991, folder 1 of 2 (Box 356)
    - Prison Law Monitor, 1978-1991, folder 2 of 2 (Box 357)
    - Veteran's Advocate, 1989-1992, 2 folders (Box 357)
    - Print Material by Topic
      - ACLU Chapter Events (Box 358)
      - ACLU National Briefings, 2000 Sept. (Box 358)
      - ACLU-NC Profiles (Box 358)
      - ACLU-NC Publicity and Events (Box 358)
      - ACLU National Newsletters, 1999-2001 (Box 358)
      - ACLU Pamphlets and Mailings (Box 358)
      - ACLU Pro/Con, 4 folders (Box 358)
      - ACLU regional newsletters (Box 358)
      - Banned books (Box 358)
      - Bill of Rights, general (Box 358)
      - Censorship (Box 359)
      - Civil Liberties Reports, 1981, 1994, 1999 (Box 359)
      - Civil Liberties Reports, 1999, 2000 (Box 359)
      - Civil Liberties, Restoring Civil Liberties, 1992 (Box 359)
      - Civil Rights, 1981-1984 (Box 359)
      - Death penalty (Box 359)
      - Deposition, 1982, 1988 (Box 359)
      - Driving While Black reports, 1999-2002 (Box 359)
      - Drugs, 1995-1996 (Box 359)
      - Fillers (Box 359)
      - Free Speech/Free Press (Box 359)
      - God and Country publication (Box 359)
      - Grassroots Lobbying Packets (Box 360)
      - Housing and Homelessness, 1977, 1987, 1996 (Box 360)
      - Immigration and Alien Rights, 1983 (Box 360)
      - Immigration and Alien Rights, 1993-1994 (Box 360)
      - Legislative Reports, 1999 (Box 360)
      - Gay/Lesbian Civil Rights (Box 360)
      - Same-Sex Marriage (Box 360)
      - Gay/Lesbian "Know Your Rights" Brochure (Box 360)
      - LGBT Rights AIDS/HIV reports, 2000-2001 (Box 360)
      - Litigation Reports, 1999 (Box 360)
      - McCarthy (Box 360)
      - Media, 1994 (Box 360)
      - Police Abuse Project, NAACP, 1988-1990 (Box 360)
      - Police Abuse, NAACP, 1991 (Box 361A)
      - "When Stopped by Police" Card, 1996 (Box 361A)
      - Privacy, 1996 (Box 361A)
      - Police, 1993-1996 (Box 361A)
      - Religious Liberty, 1995-1996, 4 folders (Box 361A)
      - Reproductive Freedom, 1983, 1989 (Box 361A)
      - Reproductive Freedom, 1998-2000 (Box 361A)
      - Skokie, 2 folders (Box 361A)
      - Speeches, 1976-1986, 3 folders (Box 361B)
      - Students' Rights, Reports and Resource Packets, 1991, 2000 (Box 361B)
      - Students' Rights, "Ask Sybil Liberty" Handout Series (Box 361B)
      - Voting Rights, redistricting, 2001 (Box 361B)
      - Women's Rights, report, 2001 (Box 362)
      - Gender Equity, Women's Rights, 1996 (Box 362)
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 362)
    - The Working Parts, 1973-1979, 2 folders (Box 357)
    - Youth Law News, 1984-1990, 4 folders (Box 357)
- Oversize Material, 1 folder
  - Large black and white photographic print, Barbara Jordan with unknown African American judge [possibly John Charles Thomas of Virginia Supreme Court at swearing-in], 1983 [News and Observer, Raleigh, NC?] (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Redistricting maps, Harnett County, NC, 1990s (Oversize-folder 1)
- Accession (2013-0209), 1985-2011, 5 boxes, 1 Ovs Folder
  Includes files relating to the ACLU of North Carolina's work on immigration and immigrant rights (such as racial profiling at driver checkpoints and english-only legislation), education, and TASER policy and use by North Carolina law enforcement. Also includes a small set of historical files belonging to Frank Goldsmith.
  - Historical Files, 1985-2002
    - ACLU-NC Meeting Minutes, 1985-2002, 3 folders (Box 363)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 1978-1979, 1 Ovs Folder (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Immigration Files, 2007-2009
    - Beaufort County English Only Policy,2007-2008 (Box 363)
    - Cabarrus County 287(g) program, 2006-2007, 2 folders (Box 363)
    - Conducting Checkpoint Driver Surveys, 2008 (Box 363)
    - Dillard Drive Middle School, 2008, 2 folders (Box 364)
    - Legislation and Resolutions, 2007-2009 (Box 364)
    - Ordinances, 2008 (Box 364)
    - Rebecca Headen planner, 2008 (Box 364)
    - School and Education Issues, 2008 (Box 364)
    - "Secure Communities", 2009 (Box 364)
  - Taser Project, 2003-2011
    - 2011 Electronic Control Weapon Guidelines, 2011 (Box 364)
    - ACLU, "A Force to Be Reckoned With", 2011 (Box 364)
    - ACLU, "Conducted Energy Devices Guidelines and Limitations", 2009 (Box 364)
    - John Wayne Paylor Case, 2009 (Box 364)
    - News Articles, TASER Incidents in North Carolina, 2011 (Box 364)
    - "Not There Yet, The Need for Safer TASER Policies in North Carolina", 2008 (Box 364)
    - Taser Case Law, 2003-2007, 2 folders (Box 364)
    - Taser Death, Richard E. McKinnon Case, 2007 (Box 365)
    - Taser Death, Shannon Lane Johnson Case, 2006-2007, 2 folders (Box 365)
    - Taser News Articles, 2007 (Box 365)
    - Taser Notes, 2007 (Box 365)
    - Taser Policy, Response from NC Sheriff Departments, 2008 (Box 365)
    - Taser Project, Correspondence, 2007-2009 (Box 365)
    - Taser Project, Correspondence with NC County Sheriffs, 2008-2009 (Box 365)
    - Taser Project, Correspondence, NC Sheriff Departments, 2007-2008 (Box 365)
    - Taser Public Records Requests, 2007 (Box 365)
    - Taser Questionnaire for NC Sheriff Departments, 2007 (Box 365)
    - Taser Research, 2004-2006, 2 folders (Box 366)
    - Taser Research, 2009 (Box 366)
    - Taser Research Notes, 2006 (Box 366)
    - Taser Use Survey by NC County, 2007, 6 folders (Box 366)
    - Taser Use Survey by NC City, 2007, 4 folders (Box 367)
    - Richard McKinnon Case, 2005-2007 (Box 368)
    - Shannon Johnson Case, 2006 (Box 368)
    - ACLU Taser Report, 2007 (Box 368)
    - TASER International Training Bulletin, 2005-2007 (Box 368)
    - TASER Police Training, 2007 (Box 368)
    - Cumberland County Jail tour, 2006 (Box 368)
    - SPD Taser use, 2001-2003 (Box 368)
    - ACLU Florida-North Carolina Correspondence, 2007 (Box 368)
    - Commentary- Kyle Ross, 2007 (Box 368)
    - TASER Operating Manual, 2004 (Box 368)
    - TASER International Training, 2004; 1 of 2 (Box 368)
    - TASER International Training, 2004; 2 of 2 (Box 368)
    - Wilson Police Department In-Service Training, 2006; 1 of 5 (Box 368)
    - Wilson Police Department In-Service Training, 2006; 2 of 5 (Box 368)
    - Wilson Police Department In-Service Training, 2006; 3 of 5 (Box 368)
    - Wilson Police Department In-Service Training, 2006; 4 of 5 (Box 368)
    - Wilson Police Department In-Service Training, 2006; 5 of 5 (Box 368)
    - ACLU of NC faxes, 2007 (Box 368)
    - "A Citizen's Guide on Using the Freedom of Information Act and the Privacy Act of 1974 to Request Government Records", 1997 (Box 368)
    - Union County Officer Training, 2005-2007 (Box 368)
    - Shannon Johnson Police Reports, 2006-2007 (Box 369)
    - Gastonia Police Department Public Records, 2009 (Box 369)
    - Charlotte-Mecklenburg Police Department Camera Program, 2007-2009; 1 of 4 (Box 369)
    - Charlotte-Mecklenburg Police Department Camera Program, 2007-2009; 2 of 4 (Box 369)
    - Charlotte-Mecklenburg Police Department Camera Program, 2007-2009; 3 of 4 (Box 369)
    - Charlotte-Mecklenburg Police Department Camera Program, 2007-2009; 4 of 4 (Box 369)
    - Jacksonville Police Department Tag Recognition, 2008-2009 (Box 369)
    - Cabarrus County Gang Violence Prevention Grant, 2009 (Box 369)
    - Fayetteville Video Surveillance Program, 2008-2009 (Box 369)
    - High Point Public Records, 2009 (Box 369)
    - Asheville Public Records, 2009 (Box 369)
    - Raleigh Public Records, 2009 (Box 369)
  - Other, 2
    - Pena vs. Porter, 2007-2008; 1 of 3 (Box 370)
    - Pena vs. Porter, 2007-2008; 2 of 3 (Box 370)
    - Pena vs. Porter, 2007-2008; 3 of 3 (Box 370)
    - Cary Video Surveillance Records, 2009 (Box 370)
    - Wilmington Video Surveillance Project, 2007-2009; 1 of 2 (Box 370)
    - Wilmington Video Surveillance Project, 2007-2009; 2 of 2 (Box 370)
    - Wilson County Video Surveillance Project, 2006-2009 (Box 370)
    - Automated Liscence Plate Reader research, 2007-2010 (Box 371)
    - Letters to ACLU, 2007; 1 of 2 (Box 371)
    - Letters to ACLU, 2007; 2 of 2 (Box 371)
    - Letters of complaint- San Diego Correctional Facility, 2006-2007 (Box 371)
    - Letters to ACLU from NC prisoners, 2005-2006; 1 of 4 (Box 371)
    - Letters to ACLU from NC prisoners, 2005-2006; 2 of 4 (Box 371)
    - Letters to ACLU from NC prisoners, 2005-2006; 3 of 4 (Box 371)
    - Letters to ACLU from NC prisoners, 2005-2006; 4 of 4 (Box 371)
    - Letter of Complaint, 2006 (Box 371)
    - ACLU NC Court of Appeals, 2005 (Box 371)
    - ACLU NC Court of Appeals, 2006 (Box 371)
    - NC Inmate Grievance Resolution Board Correspondence, 2006 (Box 371)
    - Police Brutality, Carrabus County, 2007; 1 of 2 (Box 371)
    - Police Brutality, Carrabus County, 2007; 2 of 2 (Box 371)
- Web Content Series, 2011-2020; 2011-ongoing
  - ACLU of North Carolina website, 2011-2020; 2011-ongoing
  - ACLU of North Carolina Twitter, 2012-2020; 2012-ongoing
  - ACLU of North Carolina Facebook, 2012-2020; 2012-ongoing
  - ACLU Capital Punishment Project, 2014-2020; 2014-ongoing
  - ACLU of North Carolina YouTube, 2015-2020; 2015-ongoing